I want to talk about and I pray I I want
to take time whatever I'm teaching is
something that I believe has to be
understood. So let me have this cage.
Somebody come and carry it and then put
a seat inside.
I want to teach with demonstration.
Just bring it here. Can it come?
Yes. Uh yeah, thank you. Thank you.
Yeah, put it. Yeah, you can put it
there. Yes.
for st.
And then
um I want my brother from the worship
team. You come. You look like a good
character for this scene.
Yeah. Come with your notebook if you
want to write anything. You'll stay here
for long. We are preaching together and
you got the assignment right.
Open the door and let the culprit enter.
Okay. So, I want you to sit inside
and close that door. That's the jail.
And then
mama,
you're the one watching and guarding
that jail because this man cannot leave
until we meet the demand. He has an
offense of sin and the demand is death.
So unless we meet the demand of death,
this man cannot leave the jail.
Now I want us to go to the scriptures
and look at the book of Matthew chapter
number 11. Matthew 11 uh not 11 Matthew
28 and verse 11. I'll share a couple of
scriptures and then I'll lay the matter.
I want to talk about the mystery of Bar
Abbas.
The mystery of Bar Abbas. I know even me
sometimes I call him Banabas but we will
understand that the name is not Babas
but the name is Bar Abbas.
The mystery of Bar Abbas.
The Bible says, "Now
while they were going, behold,
some of the guard came into the city and
reported to the chief priests
all the things that had happened.
When they had assembled with the elders
and consulted together, they gave a
large sum of money to the soldiers,
saying, "Tell them, his disciples came
at night and stole him away while we
slept,
and if this come to the governor's ear,
we will appease him and make you
secure."
So they took the money and did as they
were instructed. And this saying is
commonly reported among the Jews until
this day.
Let us look also
I want us to read the scriptures and
then we'll come to the matter. Luke 22
from verse 1 to verse 6. I want you to
see the matter because there's a there's
a place where the the verse says if if
they understand about the resurrection,
if they knew about the resurrection is
going to be a bad thing. But in this
one, the Bible says now the feasts of
the unleven bread drew near which is
called Passover.
And the chief priests, I want you to
keep on underlining the word chief
priests.
And the scribes sought how they might
kill him, for they feared the people.
Then Satan entered Judas, son named
Escariot, who was numbered among the 12.
So he went his way and conferred with
the chief priests and captains how he
might betray him to them.
And they were glad and agreed to give
him money.
So he promised and sought opportunity to
betray him to them in the absence of the
multitude.
Let us jump to Luke 23 from verse 11.
Luke 23 from verse 11.
Then Herod with his men of war treated
him with contempt and mocked him and
raided him in a gorgeous robe and sent
him back to Pilate.
That very day Pilate and Herod became
friends with each other for previously
they had been at enemity with each
other.
Then Pilate, when he had called together
the chief priest, the rulers and the
people,
said to them, "You have brought this man
to me as one who misleads the people.
And indeed, having examined him in your
presence, I have found no fault in this
man concerning those things of which you
accuse him."
nor neither did Herod, for I sent you
back to him, and indeed nothing
deserving of death has been done to him.
I WILL THEREFORE CHASTISE him and
release him,
for it was necessary for him to release
one to them at the feast.
And they all cried out at once, saying,
"Away with this man, and released to us
Bar Abas,
who had been thrown into prison
for a certain rebellion,
made in the city, and for madam."
Pilate therefore, wishing to release
Jesus again, called out to them.
But they shouted, saying, "Crucify him!
crucify him. Then he said to them that
that time, why, what evil has he done? I
have found no reason for death in him. I
will therefore chastise him and let him
go. But they were insistent, demanding
with loud voices that he he be
crucified. And the voices of these men
and of the chief priests prevailed.
So Pilate gave sentence that it should
be as they requested.
And he released to them the one they
requested who for rebellion and murder
had been thrown into prison. But he
delivered Jesus to their will.
Now as they led him away, they laid hold
of a certain man, Simeon, a Serenian,
who was coming from the country, and on
him they laid the cross that he might
bear it after Jesus. Praise the name of
the living God. Luke chapter number 3
and verse 2.
Luke chapter number 3 and verse 2.
I'm reading many scriptures and then we
just begin the vessel. If you can read,
let's all read.
While Ana ANAS AND KYIFAS WERE HIGH
PRIEST, the word of God came to John the
son of Zachariah in the wilderness. I
want you to mark because when we go to
the plurality
of the name the chief priests now we
know the names of the people their name
was Anas and who
anaz
let us look at John chapter number 18
from verse 12.
Then the detachment of the troop and the
captain and the officers of the Jews
arrested Jesus and bound him. 13 And
they led him away to announce first for
his first for he was the father-in-law
of Kyifas who was high priest that year.
Now it was Kyifers who advised the Jews
that it was expedient that one man
should die for the people. He actually
prophesied.
Uh-huh.
And Simon Peter followed Jesus and so
did another disciple. Now that disciple
was known to the high priest. That
disciple is John and that's a
conversation for another day because for
him to be known to the high priest that
means John had a very strong connection
and lineage. and we have to interrogate
where he came from. Now the the the the
there are certain things that I'm going
to mention and I pray that God will open
the ears of your understanding.
The the event of Jesus crucification and
death was engineered
100% by the chief priests.
They became the people that engineered
their death.
And the chief priest there, the name the
chief priest by the name of Anas, that
man, he had appointed according to
history five of his children to be high
priests.
He had appointed five of his children,
BUT THEY WERE FIRED BY THE ROMAN POWER.
The order of the Bible is that the high
priest was meant to come from Aon.
That was the Levitical order. And there
WERE GENEALOGIES IN THE temple that any
man that DESIRED OR ANY MAN THAT WAS
MEANT TO BE coronoted into the office of
a high priest, he needed to locate his
lineage from Aaron.
But something happened uh in the in the
in the in the centuries after Malachi
the last prophet something happened
historically
the what we call the 400 years of
silence something happened and we call
it the Makabis revolt. Makabis revolt.
In the Makabes revolt, we lost the
pattern of appointing priest from the
lineage of Aaron. After the revolt came,
the people who are serving in the temple
never came from Aaron. And then Rome
colonized the Israelites. AND BY THAT
COLONIZATION,
Rome became so powerful because it was
Rome that actually appointed and fired
the priest that serve in the temple. So
we are coming from the order of Aaron.
There is a reol and the and the ironic
priesthood is messed up. BUT IF YOU
KNOW, YOU UNDERSTAND THE priesthood of
Aaron must be intercepted so that the
order of Melkisedc can enter. So now the
PRIESTHOOD OF AARON IS AFFECTED. The
Makabist revolution, the Makabes
revolution, that's where we get the book
of Makabis. The Makabes revolution was a
product. There is a man prophesied by
Daniel and his name was Antiocus
Epiphanis.
the the the description of the man
Antiocus Epiphan is in the book of
Daniel many people think that is the
antichrist because he came and fought
the order of worship. He slaughtered a
pig in the temple of Yahweh. He stopped
circumcision of the Jews. He came and
told the people that that they should
not even worship from the temple and and
he fought Judaism AND OUT OF THAT he was
a Greek man. OUT OF THAT A SECT OF MEN
ROSE AND THEY BEGAN TO FIGHT ANTIOCUS
AND THAT SECT OF MEN was called the
MAKABIS AND THEY WON IN THE MAKABIS war
and THE ORDER OF WORSHIP was restored
and the temple sacrifices were
reinitiated. Daniel saw it. He spoke
about the abomination of desolation in
the prophecies. It was a very dark time
in the days of the prophetic.
AND SO AFTER the Mcabes after THE MCABES
ORDER NOW THE PRIEST WERE BEING
APPOINTED by Rome and this appointment
came because of the interest of Rome. So
Rome is a superpower AND THEY ARE THE
ones controlling the worship of the
temple. They are the ones appointing the
priest and there was a reason and the
reason was the temple WAS NOT JUST A
BUILDING. IT was an economic center.
THERE WERE ALMOST A MILLION JEWS.
50,000 of them lived in Jerusalem.
AND THERE WERE SEVEN JUDAISTIC festivals
that every male Jew had to attend. And
part of that was the Passover and the
Pentecost festival. AND THERE WAS A LOT
OF SACRIFICE IN THESE FESTIVALS. So the
temple commanded a lot of resources. YOU
CAN IMAGINE A MILLION people sacrificing
to God on one altar. THE INTENSITY OF
MONEY, THE ECONOMIC POWER IN THE TEMPLE
WAS HIGH. And so WE DON'T KNOW WHO
APPOINTED ANANAS. BUT WE KNOW THAT
ANANAS, THE priest was appointed, but
later he was taken out. But after BEING
TAKEN OUT, THE HAND OF ANANAS WAS still
present CONTROLLING THE ORDER AND THE
TEMPLE.
So the MAN IS NO LONGER AN ACTIVE
PRIEST.
He has APPOINTED FIVE OF HIS SONS. NONE
OF THEM SUCCEEDS. HE HAS NOW APPOINTED A
SON-IN-LAW,
KYIFAS,
who is the one that is now taking
charge. So this is like A FAMILY
BUSINESS. YOU KNOW I READ THIS THING AND
I began to say so this thing began
early. SO ANANAS IS NOT THE ONE RUNNING
THE SHOW BUT IS ACTUALLY THE ONE RUNNING
the show. ACTUALLY THE THE PROBLEM OF
ANANAS AND KYIFAS AND Jesus began IN THE
TRIUMPH ENTRY OF JESUS TO JERUSALEM.
WHEN JESUS ENTERED into Jerusalem he
went straight to the temple. when he
entered into the temple, HE OVERTURNED
THE THE THE tables of the money changers
and he SET FREE THE ANIMALS. NOW, Ananas
and Kyifas in the temple they had a
PORTION WHERE THEY ALLOCATED men places
to CHANGE MONEY AND PLACES TO SELL
ANIMAL FOR SACRIFICE. SO, this was their
personal business.
This was their personal business and
they they they played so unfair. I think
you need to work on my mic and I don't
know what I'm struggling but just find
my levels. It was so unfair because
in the temple there was a place where
PEOPLE CAME AND BOUGHT ANIMAL for
sacrifice and when you came with that
different money you had to exchange to
what they called the temple currency. So
let me give a practical example. You are
coming from Mombasa and there is only
one temple in Nairobi. YOU CANNOT CARRY
A GOAT from Mombasa.
So you literally come to the temple and
you are told this is the goat for
sacrifice. It has no blemish. So you
come and buy the goat and you PAY AND
WHERE YOU ARE COMING FROM MOMBASA the
money we use in Nairobi is not the same
currency. SO YOU MUST CHANGE your money
to what we call THE TEMPORAL CURRENCY.
THE MONEY THAT the temple accepts is an
offering. So there was something like a
FOREX TRADE AND THERE WAS A place where
animals WERE SOLD. SO ANANAS AND HIS
COMPANION, THIS CHIEF PRIEST, what they
did, THEY CONTROLLED THAT MARKET. THEY
APPOINTED PEOPLE THAT DISQUALIFIED THE
SACRIFICES OF MEN SO THAT THEY CAN BUY
THEIR ANIMALS. THEY WERE SELLING THEIR
ANIMALS AT INFLATED PRICES. THEIR
EXCHANGE RATE WAS AT AN INFLATED RATE.
And so they were doing business with the
people.
THEY WERE RUNNING THE BUSINESS IN THE
CHURCH. AND THAT IS WHY WHEN JESUS CAME,
HE TARGETED THE MERCHANTS, THE MONEY
CHANGERS AND THE ANIMALS AND HE
OVERTURNED THEM. THAT IS WHEN THE DOOR
WAS OPEN FOR THEM TO PLOT FOR the death
of Jesus BECAUSE HE WAS ACTUALLY
AFFECTING THEIR economy and their
operation.
YOU KNOW, I READ THAT THING AND I saw
the church. Sorry to say so.
THE FIRST THING I SAW IS THE PATTERN
WHEREBY WE WANT TO MAKE CHURCH A FAMILY
BUSINESS.
OKAY? You know, please forgive me
because uh it looks like WE CANNOT
RAISE. I HAVE NO PROBLEM AND I KEEP ON
saying this. I HAVE NO PROBLEM IF MY SON
INHERITS my mantle. I'll be one of the
happiest fathers. it will remain in the
family. But I HAVE A PROBLEM WHEN I
BYPASS SONS that have been raised in the
HOUSE AND I FAIL TO PRAY TO ASK THE LORD
WHO IS SUPPOSED TO take over me and I
begin TO PUSH MY SON TO TAKE OVER. That
is the pattern of the chief priests.
Can we have church?
>> I READ THIS SCRIPTURE AND IT BEGAN TO
POINT TO ME AND SHOW ME WHATEVER IS
HAPPENING IN SOME CHURCHES IS NOT OF
GOD. WE HAVE INTRODUCED THE MONEY
CHANGERS BUSINESS AND WE HAVE INTRODUCED
THE ANIMAL BUSINESS WHEREBY IT IS NO
LONGER ABOUT THE BLOOD ALONE. IT IS NO
LONGER ABOUT CHRIST ALONE. IT IS BLOOD
and anointing oil. It is Christ and some
water. IT IS BLOOD AND THE NAME OF JESUS
AND HANDKERCHIEF. IT IS BLOOD THE NAME
OF JESUS and
a seed.
JESUS CAME. HE TOOK AWAY the rituals. HE
OVERTURNED THE TABLES AND SAID, "MY
HOUSE, THIS IS NOT THE HOUSE OF ANY MAN.
IT IS THE HOUSE OF ELOHIM." HE SAID, "MY
HOUSE SHALL BE CALLED THE HOUSE OF
PRAYER, BUT NOT A DEN OF THIEVES.
ANYWHERE THE REVELATION OF CHRIST
ENTERS,
the money lenders,
the table OF THE MONEY CHANGERS
AND
THOSE WHO ARE DOING BUSINESS WITH THE
GOSPEL, they always enter a loss.
And when you read that scripture in
Matthew, THE BIBLE SAYS AFTER JESUS
OVERTURN THE TABLE OF THE MONEY LENDERS
AFTER DOING AN OPERATION IN THE HOUSE,
THE BIBLE says it is in the book of
Matthew. Maybe you can get the
scripture. THE BIBLE SAYS, "THEN THE
LAME, the blind, and the sick and the
weak began to come to church." Hi, I
DISCOVERED PLEASE TAKE ME TO MATTHEW,
the one that is there. If after the
triumphantry when you look when Jesus
said give me get me two donkeys
and he walked into Jerusalem he needed
two donkeys to walk into Jerusalem. When
he got inside AFTER TURNING AFTER
TURNING THE TABLES of the moneylanders
THE BIBLE SAYS AND SUDDENLY THE WEAK the
blind began to come to the temple. THEN
THE BLIND GO TO 13. Go to 13. And he
said to them everybody read. And he said
to them, "It is written, MY HOUSE SHALL
BE CALLED A HOUSE OF PRAYER, BUT YOU
HAVE made it a den of a den OF THIEVES."
SO AFTER THERE IS A CLEANSING OF THE
HOUSE,
SUDDENLY THE PEOPLE THAT NEED THE HOUSE
WILL BEGIN TO COME.
>> Look at the next verse. THE BIBLE SAYS,
"THEN THE BLIND AND the lame came to him
in the temple and he HEALED THEM." THEY
NEVER WENT TO THE MONEY CHANGERS. THEY
NEVER WENT TO THE PLACE OF SACRIFICE.
THEY KNEW THE ONE THAT TAKES CHARGE OF
THE TEMPLE IS NOW is in his house. They
came to him.
>> How did THE BLIND KNOW?
HOW did the lame know?
There is a level of consecration
that automatically begins to attract.
The Bible says when I'm lifted, I draw
men to myself. You can do crusades, but
you are doing them to grow in the church
so that the offering can grow.
You can do CRUSADES SO THAT MEMBERSHIP
CAN GROW. BUT YOU can also do crusades
so that Jesus can be glorified. It is
only him who knows THE MOTIVE OF YOUR
HEART.
This is where the problem began.
When Jesus touched the business of Anas
and Kyifers,
that's when the beef and the problem
began. These men were not small people.
They were controlling the religion of
Jerusalem.
They had the masses on their side. But
when you look at Luke chapter number 3
and verse two, it begins to give you
very strange signals because it tells
you though there was a priesthood,
THE LORD BYPASSED THEM and spoke to
John.
SO HEAVEN NEVER RECOGNIZED THEM BECAUSE
IF HEAVEN RECOGNIZED THE PRIESTHOOD OF A
NURSE AND KYIFERS, GOD would have spoken
to them because a priest was a man that
did business on the altar. HE'S A MAN
THAT INVOKED THE PRESENCE AND THE POWER
of God. The altar WAS STILL THERE.
SACRIFICES were still there, but the
voice of God was not there. When you
look FROM MALACHI, THE FIRST TIME THE
VOICE OF GOD WAS HEARD AGAIN in the
territories of Israel, it was not by a
prophet.
It was by God himself say this is my son
with whom I'm well pleased with.
So there was a distorted priesthood and
Kyifers God cannot partner with them.
These are businessmen.
Yesterday we were driving somewhere and
a friend of mine told me nowadays to
ordain a bishop is 1 million
Ronnie I need to ordain you
to ordain a reverend it's around 250
and and can I just come apostolically
sir
>> and and and when you go to when we look
at those ordinations
per the standards of this book. Whatever
we are doing are rituals that are Old
Testament.
They are not in the covenant of Christ.
The clothes we are wearing are from
Rome. They never came from Jesus.
WE HAVE RETURNED THE CHURCH BACK TO THE
DAYS OF SACRIFICE WHEREAS THE FINAL
SACRIFICE WAS OFFERED ON THE CROSS.
You know ah
I looked at one ordination I was almost
crying. I said Lord.
Then the Lord spoke to me and he told me
what people have done they have picked
all the spiritual parts of the Bible and
they have put them together because
spirituality demands discipline and when
you are disciplined you need to get
results. So men are no longer
questioning the process. Men are after
results. That's why we must be taught of
the word. Somebody say Ananas. Anas
>> and Kyifers.
>> So what happened? So this man began to
plot how are we going to bring this man
down? The system is already hacked. The
temple business is already affected. You
can imagine managing a temple where
every every day you have 50,000 Jews in
Jerusalem and in every festival we have
a million people coming from diaspora
and they are coming to worship and part
of the worship in Passover they must buy
the Passover lamb and let's assume even
just half a million are doing it and you
are the custodian of all the sheep they
going to slaughter. They come with their
ship and say no this does not match the
standards of the temple. They are coming
with their money to exchange and you
have inflated the price. AND SO WHEN
JESUS COMES ON BOARD BECAUSE HE begins
to open the eyes of the people in
scripture, he becomes a hindrance. And
so they plot for the demise and the
death of Christ and they become the ones
that are the ones handling the process.
THESE ARE THE MEN THAT paid Judas.
They told HIM AND THEY BID HIM FROM THE
TEMPLE treasury
because they were THE CUSTODIANS OF THE
TEMPLE. THEY TOOK A PART OF THE money
and paid him and the money they paid him
was an insult BECAUSE THE MONEY THEY
PAID HIM WAS THE VALUE OF A SLAVE.
THAT'S HOW THEY HAD REDUCED THE savior
that will bribe YOU WITH MONEY WORTH THE
PRICE OF A SLAVE. THAT'S THE MAN we're
going to give you for you to hand over
Jesus.
So the number is still INCREASING AND SO
WE ARE MOVING FROM THIS MAN. JUDAS HAS
NOW COME ON BOARD. All these are people
that the enemy is partnering with
BECAUSE THE POWERFUL HAND BEHIND THESE
PEOPLE is the hand of Lucifer.
But again WHAT THEY DON'T UNDERSTAND
THERE IS AN ANCIENT MATRIX. Everything
they are doing was prophesied. They have
to play the script.
And so they come now and they have
arrested him. And this was the worst
part when they took Jesus at night.
I know we've READ THE BIBLE, BUT I'M
TRYING TO OPEN BECAUSE AS I WAS DOING
THIS STUDY, THE LORD TOLD ME, YOU KNOW,
YOU HAVE BEEN TEACHING EASTER, BUT BUT
THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS MEANT BY PASS.
Do you know when they arrested JESUS
AT THAT NIGHT AGAINST THE LAW, THEY TOOK
HIM FIRST TO THE HOUSE OF an ass.
According to the law, you are not meant
to be interrogated at night.
It was against the law. So they took him
to the house AND THEY TORTURED HIM. THAT
IS WHEN PETER DENIED JESUS. It was the
court IN A MAN'S HOUSE, A PRIEST. They
were slapping HIM, BLINDFOLDING HIM,
ASKING HIM, "WHO SLAPPED YOU?" AND THEN
THEY ASKED HIM, "ARE YOU the Messiah?"
BECAUSE THEY WERE ALSO CAREFUL NOT TO
KILL the Messiah.
BECAUSE THE TORAH WAS VERY CLEAR, A
SAVIOR will come to deliver Israel. And
they asked him, are you THE MESSIAH? AND
JESUS ANSWERED them and said, Just as
you have said it, he answered it.
But this is the paradox. THE WHOLE OF
THE NATION OF ISRAEL WAS waiting for a
MILITANT MESSIAH. BUT THE ONE WHO CAME
BEGAN TO TELL them when you are slapped
on this side, give the other side. Pray
for those who offend you. Forgive those
who are who are offending you. Now,
right now
in the season of one term, two term and
elections are becoming very radical and
then you hear there is a man who will
come to save Kenya. You look at the
economy and all that and then the man
comes and says hallelujah forgive those
who have stolen from you. Love those who
have looted from you and forgive them
and those who have stolen return seven
times. I won't lie to you Buddha
in revolution. We are not here for
sympathy. We want Israel back. THAT WAS
THE ATTITUDE OF ISRAEL. They were
waiting for a military man who will come
and tell them the time of Rome is over.
WE IT IS NOW FOR US TO TAKE OVER
MILITARILY AND OVERCOME THEM AND DELIVER
OUR people from the yolks and the
bondage. And you'll understand why they
asked for Barnabas.
So, so, SO THEY WAITED FOR SUCH A MAN.
SO THE WHOLE OF ISRAEL WAS DISAPPOINTED
BECAUSE WE ARE UNDER ROME. WE NEED A
SAVIOR. YET THE MAN IS TELLING US TO
FORGIVE OUR ENEMIES. HOW MANY TIMES
SHOULD WE FORGIVE? 70 * 70. ARE YOU
SERIOUS? SUCH A TIME WE NEED A
REVOLUTIONARIST. WE NEED A MAN THAT CAN
TAKE US TO THE STREETS FROM MANDO and
you're telling us to forgive. Let me
tell you if you in that day you would
also have crucified him
BECAUSE THE EXPECTATION VERSUS
manifestation never matched.
And so they look at him and they think
just another radical believer a read of
the Torah
or just as followers. IN THE MORNING IS
WHEN THEY TOOK HIM to Kyifas in the
morning. SO THERE WAS A WHOLE NIGHT
INTERROGATION UNDER Ananas
and THEN IN THE MORNING THEY NOW TAKE
HIM TO KYIFAS. THE ONE THAT NOW AT LEAST
sat legally.
Kyifas was also the leader of what we
call the Sanhedrin. Somebody say the
Sanhedrin.
>> Somebody say the Sanhedrin.
>> Who are the Sanhedrin?
This was a a court of elders WHO SAT TO
DETERMINE cases concerning the people.
SO THE HIGH PRIEST SAT AS THE CHIEF
judge
and the ELDERS CAME FROM THE COURT OF
THE PHARISEES AND THE COURT OF THE
SADDUCEES.
THAT'S WHY ANY MATTER THAT WAS ATTACKING
Israel needed the court of the SANHEDRIN
AND THE COURT OF THE SANHEDRIN met and
they made a ruling and said we don't
need this man because they did not have
power to kill Jesus. Now they had to
take him to Pilate because they were
under Roman colony. So you cannot kill
Jesus yet YOU ARE UNDER THE COLONY OF
ROME. YOU HAVE NO POWER FOR CAPITAL
EXECUTION. So you must GO TO THE ONE
THAT HAS THE POWER AND NEGOTIATE with
Rome whether you can crucify him.
AND PILATE ASKED THEM, "Is this a matter
of your faith and teachings?" Then he
told them, "LISTEN, THIS MAN IS FROM
GALILEE." "YES, do this. Take him to
Herod BECAUSE HEROD IS THE LEADER IN
GALILEE. I am a prefect in the
TERRITORIES OF ROME. BUT HEROD IS THE
LEADER THERE. He's the king there. So
take him to Herod. THIS HEROD WAS THE
SON OF THE HEROD WHOSE who wanted to
kill Jesus. SO HE WAS THE SON. AND THIS
HEROD HAD a problem because HE HAD HEARD
ABOUT JESUS. And when he was taken to
Herod, Jesus never answered Herod. And
Herod realized he cannot do anything
because Herod wanted a miracle. HE NOW
GAVE HIM A PURPLE GARMENT AS A SIGN OF
MOCKERY AND HE SAID TAKE HIM BACK TO
PILATE BECAUSE I HAVE NO POWER FOR
PUNISHMENT.
AND AS THEY TOOK HIM BACK TO PILATE,
THIS IS WHERE NOW THE DRAMA UNFOLDS. THE
OFFENSE OF ANANAS AND KYIFAS, THEY HAD
TO CONVINCE PILATE TO MAKE A ruling by
mobilizing a crowd.
I pray for understanding.
So
the TEAM OF ANANAS AND KYIFERS MOBILIZED
AND THEY HAD THE MOBILIZATION STRATEGY
because they the ones who operated in
the temple. They mobilized the people.
When you hear the Bible say that the
voice of the PEOPLE WAS MORE THAN THE
VOICE OF PILATE. IT WAS a mobilized
crowd.
>> THIS WAS A BATTLE BETWEEN THE HIGH
PRIEST and Jesus.
THESE MEN WERE MOBILIZED BECAUSE ON THE
EASTERN SIDE THESE ARE THE men who laid
their garments on the ground. ON THE
WESTERN SIDE THESE ARE THE MEN WHO ARE
SHOUTING crucify him.
It was a mobilized crowd. And so they
are part of that and they go and they
appear before Pilate.
Pilate
was a leader. Let's assume like a member
of parliament of Kamu.
They call them the preets. He was
employed by Caesar.
Caesar was the leader of Rome.
And history says THERE WERE TWO riots
in the days of Pilate.
And the riots were not very good because
some Jews died.
That's why the Bible says whe when when
when Pilate and Herod, they were united
because of Jesus. Because Herod
positioned himself as the king of the
Jews. SO WHEN THE PEOPLE DIED, THERE WAS
AN ENEMITY. SO PILATE HAD A WARNING from
Caesar BECAUSE THE WORK OF A LEADER AND
A PREFECT IS TO MAKE SURE THERE IS peace
in your territory.
SO NOW HERE IS A MAN BROUGHT BY A
MULTITUDE AND A NURSE AND KYAS
UNDERSTAND THE PSYCHOLOGY OF POLITICS.
THEY MUST PUSH PILOT TO THE WALL UNTIL
they get what THEY WANT. SO PILATE IS
NOT IN VERY GOOD TERMS WITH CAESAR. He
has a warning because IT LOOKED LIKE HE
CANNOT MAINTAIN THE TERRITORY of Israel.
THERE HAS DIFFERENT UPRISING. THERE WERE
DIFFERENT MEN IN ISRAEL THAT WERE CALLED
THE ZEALOT. THESE WERE men who brought
war AND UPRISINGS. SO PILATE had a
warning FROM CAESAR. HERE NOW IS JESUS
BROUGHT LITERALLY HE REALIZES HE CANNOT
do anything. The man IS INNOCENT. THE
FACT THAT HE'S SUPPOSED TO EXECUTE,
THERE must be evidence of execution. THE
MAN HAS NOT DONE anything wrong. And
when you read your Bible, this is what
the Bible says. The people, the Kyif
team looked at him and told him, "This
man said that we should not pay taxes to
Caesar.
And if you do not crucify him, we will
know Caesar is not your friend."
That political statement is what made
Pilate wash his hand and say the blood
of this man let it be upon not be upon
me. And guess the carelessness of Anas
and Kyifers is they said let it be upon
us and our children. That's how radical
they were in this execution.
And so Pilate washed his hands and he
said now there's something that we do
every Passover. we have to release one
of the thiefs or one of the man that is
chaotic.
And on that day he suggested a very bad
man who was known among the Jews by the
name of Bar Apas.
This man had led a revolt
and riot.
This man had committed murder
according to the laws of the Jews. The
man was waiting for execution.
And the only way the Jews EXECUTED
MEN THAT had committed revolt in a
territory, the only way of execution was
by crucifying them. And they will
crucify them IN THE ENTRANCE OF THE CITY
OR THE WALLS OF THE CITY SO THAT THE
WHOLE NATION CAN SEE and introduce the
psychology of fear. So here is a man who
has committed a crime.
He has COMMITTED A CRIME AGAINST THE
STANDARDS of Rome. HE'S A MAN OF REVOLT.
HE'S A MURDERER. He's in jail. And he's
supposed to die by crucifixion.
Hallelujah.
>> Pish come.
Here is another man.
This man, all he did was to preach the
gospel, heal the sick, feed them, and do
all that. Even Pilate has confirmed this
man is innocent.
The secular powers and the religious
powers have confirmed this man has no
sin.
And the people are there shouting. They
are looking at Jesus and Jesus is and
and Pilate is telling them allow me to
release Jesus
instead of Barnabas because you you
CLAIM THAT THIS MAN IS A SINNER BUT HE
IS IN A SEASON OF PARDON. Let me pardon
him because I see no error. I don't know
what I'll tell Rome as to why I killed
this man. At least I have a record for
THIS MAN BUT I have nothing against this
man. And the Bible says the people began
to shout and they said, "Crucify him.
Crucify him. Crucify him." And the voice
of the people was louder than the voice
of Pilate.
And Pilate said, "There's nothing else I
can do other than fulfill your will."
And he said, "Now listen, set the
prisoner free.
Let him walk free. Ladies and gentlemen,
I want to demonstrate something here.
The man never made a prayer. The man
never gave an offering. The man never
washed the church. The man did nothing
to appease Job.
>> There is nothing he did for God to be
happy. The man just landed on mercy. And
the man walked out free
>> walking in the streets of Jerusalem AS
IF HE HAS NEVER SINNED. Ah because this
is justification. THE NAME JUSTIFICATION
MEANS JUST AS IF I HAVE NEVER SINNED. HE
WENT BACK TO HIS FREEDOM AS IF NOTHING
had happened. ALL THE FILES THAT WERE
UPON HIM HAD TO BE CANCELLED BECAUSE
ANOTHER took his place.
THE CROSS WAS NOT MEANT FOR JESUS. THE
CROSS WAS MEANT FOR BARNABAS. WHO IS
BARNABAS? It is me and you. WE WERE IN
THE JAIL OF SIN. WE DESERVE THE JUDGMENT
of God. IT IS NOTHING YOU HAVE EVER DONE
LEST YOU BEAST YOUR chest and think it
is by your works. It is by the mercies
of God. Now this is the paradox.
The name bar abas
b a r means son. Abar
means of god. There is a spirit in man
that cries aba aba.
So the name bar abar means the son of
the father.
>> Yes sir.
>> Here is the son of god.
>> IT IS A CONTENTION OF TWO SONS. BECAUSE
ADAM WAS THE SON OF the father.
>> WHAT IS A SON? HE WAS A DIRECT CREATION
OF THE FATHER. HE CAME FROM GOD. HE WAS
THE SON OF THE FATHER. BUT ADAM FELL
THROUGH SIN. ANOTHER ADAM MUST COME.
ANOTHER SON KAYA MUST SHOW UP TO UNDO
THE ERROR OF THE SON OF THE FATHER. SO
THAT THE SON OF GOD CAN DELIVER THE SON
OF THE FATHER BECAUSE WHATEVER THE SON
OF THE FATHER COULD NOT ACCOMPLISH THE
SON OF GOD CAN NOW ACCOMPLISH.
IT IS NOT A PARADOX THAT A MAN MUST BE
CALLED BAR ABAS.
IF THIS MAN DIED, WE DON'T KNOW THE NAME
OF ANY OTHER CRIMINAL.
EVEN THE ONE THAT DIED ON THE CROSS, WE
DON'T KNOW. AND YOU CAN BEGIN TO SEE
THAT DELIVERANCE BEGAN to happen on men
that were guilty. Because it cannot be
pardoning of sin if I'm not guilty. You
cannot be pardoned. You cannot BE
FORGIVEN OF THAT which you are not
guilty of.
>> YES SIR.
>> THE KIND OF MEN THAT GOT BORN AGAIN in
the interaction of Jesus. WE BEGIN WITH
BARABAS A SON OF GOD. A SON OF THE
FATHER. THIS MAN IS SET FREE NOT BECAUSE
OF ANYTHING THAT HE HAS DONE. CHURCH I
want to ASSURE YOU THIS SALVATION NEVER
CAME BY OUR WORKS. AND THAT'S WHY WE
MUST RETURN THE CHURCH BACK TO GRACE.
THERE IS A LOT OF WORK. THERE IS A LOT
OF KIBA GARAMA. LISTEN, YOU CAN NEVER
PAY ANY PRICE THAT IS ABOVE THE PRICE OF
CALVARY. THERE IS NOTHING YOU CAN DO
THAT JESUS HAS NOT DONE. THERE IS NO
LABOR. THERE IS NO PRAYER. THERE IS NO
SACRIFICE. THERE IS NO FASTING.
>> A man cannot go for seven days without
water. Jesus went for 40 days without
water and food. So you THINK NOW YOU YOU
CAN FAST MORE THAN JESUS.
You think you can outdo his fast? YOU
THINK YOU CAN SUFFER MORE THAN HIM? THE
MAN DIED FOR US. If you study what he
went through ON THE CROSS, IT'S NOT A
SMALL MATTER BECAUSE BY THE TIME THEY
WERE RELEASING the criminal, by the time
they were releasing the criminal, IT WAS
NOW TIME FOR HIM TO TAKE OVER. And they
went and tied him. They went and tied
him on a round pole. It was something
like this. And so A MAN, A MAN now kneel
down. Sorry you came in white. a man who
kneel down and tied to a pole. This was
the position. AND THEN THERE WERE TWO
MEN WITH LASHES, ONE ON THAT SIDE AND
THE OTHER ONE ON THIS SIDE WITH A LASH.
THIS MAN IS TIED BOTH HANDS AND LEGS.
AND THESE LASHES, THEY HAVE BONES AND
METAL SO THAT WHEN THEY LAND on you,
they tear YOUR FLESH. SO ONE IS WEEPING
YOU ON ONE SIDE AND THE OTHER ONE ON THE
OTHER. AND THEY ARE COUNTING AND THEY
MUST BE SENSITIVE BECAUSE the tradition
say if we give him 40 lashes he cannot
wake up.
>> So we have to give him 39. BUT WHAT THEY
DON'T UNDERSTAND THAT BY THE STRIPES OF
JESUS HEALING WAS being ministered.
>> MEDICAL SCIENCE HAS CONFIRMED THERE ARE
39 DISEASES THAT HAVE NO CURE. MEANING
THAT BY EVERY STRIKE CANCER WAS BOWING.
DIABETES, WHATEVER THEY CAN NAME UNDER
THE SUN, IT WAS BOWING. BECAUSE WHAT
THEY DIDN'T UNDERSTAND, NOT ONLY DID HE
TAKE MY PLACE, BUT HE BEGAN TO DEAL WITH
EVERYTHING THAT WAS OPPRESSING ME.
>> YES, SIR.
>> And he has to go through the shame.
Listen,
after lifting him, his whole body IS
MUTILATED. MEDICAL SCIENCE WILL TELL YOU
HE HAD MORE THAN 2,000 open wounds.
OR OR HE NEEDED 2,000 stitches that were
more than 3 in deep. That's a man that
cannot survive.
>> They take the thorns, pierce it on his
head
and PUT IT ON THE CROWN AS A CROWN. THE
BODY IS MUTILATED. THEY ARE PUTTING
COMMENTS on him
because they were trying to put HIM UNTO
SHAME. CAN I tell you the truth? WHEN
YOU UNDERSTAND some of these things
and I'm not saying you become careless
and not go to hospital, but there are
some realities you read in the Bible. I
love the faith of our mothers. THERE IS
A FAITH THAT MUST COME BACK TO CHURCH.
Yesterday I was sitting down with a
father. HE TOLD ME THE FIRST TIME HE
BOUGHT PANADOR he cried because he felt
like it WAS A BETRAYAL OF FAITH. HOW CAN
I BUY PANADOR AND JESUS DIED FOR ME?
LISTEN THERE HAS TO BE BALANCE in our
theology. But there is a level WHERE YOU
MUST ENTER. NOT EVERY cough you think
you are dying. THERE IS A LEVEL WHERE
YOU MUST KNOW BY THE STRIPES OF JESUS I
was healed. Diseases have NO PLACE IN MY
CAMP. YOU AND YOU NEED TO DECLARE IT
OVER YOUR CHILDREN OVER YOUR LIFE. YOU
NEED TO ANNOUNCE IT UNTIL IT BECOMES A
REALITY. YOUR HOME IS NOT A PHARMACY.
SOME OF YOU
YOU EVEN ADISE DOCTORS IT IS ERROR. TELL
YOUR NEIGHBOR IS ERROR. BY THE STRIPES
OF JESUS, BY THE STRIPES OF JESUS,
HEALING BECAME OUR REDEMPTION, RIGHT?
AND I WANT TO DECLARE ON THIS ALTAR, WE
ARE WALKING IN THAT REALITY. WE ARE
CANCELLING DOCTOR'S APPOINTMENTS. WE ARE
CANCELLING SURGERIES. WHATEVER THAT IS
GROWING IN YOUR BODY LEGALLY, WE COMMAND
IT TO DIE FROM THE ROOTS. WHATEVER THAT
NEVER CAME FROM THE FATHER, THE BIBLE
SAYS, I HAVE COME THAT THEY MAY HAVE
LIFE AND A LIFE INHABITANTS. ANYTHING
THAT ROBS YOUR LIFE, WE COMMAND IT TO
BOW NOW IN THE MIGHTY NAME OF JESUS. YOU
CANNOT BE A HOST OF BACTERIA. YOU CANNOT
BE A HOST OF VIRUS. WHATEVER THAT CANNOT
LIVE IN GOD, LET IT NOT LIVE IN YOU.
Doctors will TELL YOU THE FIRST HEALING
IS NOT injection is the mind. Be it
transformed by the renewal of your mind.
SOME PEOPLE
BUT THERE IS A MINDSET.
THERE IS ANOTHER MINDSET
AND I KNOW HE HEALED MY DISEASES.
THE REASON WHY IT WAS ON THE BACK
BECAUSE THE PAIN AND THE BURDEN OF
diseases is beared on THE BACK. THERE IS
A LIFTING OF THAT BURDEN. HALLELUJAH.
THERE IS A LIFTING OF that burden. YOU
DON'T UNDERSTAND WHAT IT means to go and
have a kidney transplant. That is 7
million. YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND chemo is
14 million. You don't understand what
these THINGS ARE DOING. BUT AT the end
of the day, I am here to believe AND
ACCEPT THAT THERE IS A HEALER. PASTOR,
are you trying to say everyone WILL BE
HEALED? I DON'T KNOW ABOUT EVERYONE, BUT
MY BIBLE TELLS ME WHEREVER he went, he
went and did good AND HEALED ALL. SO IT
IS POSSIBLE FOR ALL.
>> It is possible.
>> THE BIBLE SAYS THE WHOLE VILLAGE WAS
BROUGHT TO HIM. WHOLE
OF INFIRMITIES AND ALL.
>> HE'S THE SAME YESTERDAY, TODAY, AND
FOREVER MORE. WHY CAN'T WE BELIEVE HIM
IN THAT LEVEL OF THE ALL? IF HE OPEN A
BLIND EYE AND HEAL THE SICK, WHATEVER HE
DID, HE'S STILL doing
an
Kyifas. So, he has to bear he has to
bear the pain on his back for your
healing. Please tell that neighborhop
you know biology
lungs right vicle left vicle and and you
can and they have ears. You can speak to
them. You can speak to them.
>> Yeah. Can speak to them. He as then they
took her. You see these men did not even
know what they were doing.
But it's for demonstration. You see what
these things are? These are thorns.
These are thorns.
And one of the things is that when Jesus
when the son of Abba sinned
when he sinned he said now from today
when you till the ground
it will not bear any fruit because I've
cast the ground on your behalf. So
anytime you till the ground it will
produce thorns.
It will produce thorns.
The hand of God is behind the scenes but
Kyifers and Anas are thinking they're
winning but the hand of God is behind.
So some people don't understand that
what they are picking is a curse
>> and they are placing the curse on the
one that was cast so that now
>> our sweat
>> because when a man walks a man sweats.
>> Yes sir. So it was when you sweat, you
will not have fruit. You will bear
thorns. BUT FOR THERE to be redemption
of the thorns, they must also encounter
the blood. SO THAT BY YOUR SWEAT, you
will no longer have thorns. You will
begin to be productive. You will begin
to bear fruit.
THAT'S WHY AS A CHILD of destiny, as a
child of destiny,
I'm not a hustler. BY THE THORNS ON HIS
HEAD. BY THE THORNS ON HIS HEAD. UHHUH.
MY BUSINESS IS A DIFFERENT ONE. BY THE
THORNS, MY SWEAT WAS REDEEMED. IT WAS
THE DESIRE OF I WISH YOU CAN UNDERSTAND
THE DESIRE OF GOD. THE DESIRE OF GOD WAS
THAT MAN WAS NOT MEANT TO WORK. IN THE
garden of Eden, THERE WAS A RIVER THAT
BRANCH INTO SEVEN. ONE BRANCH WAS A
DIMENSION OF GOLD. THAT RIVER IS WHAT
SUPPLIED AT ADAM WITH EVERYTHING. WHEN
HE FELL, WE DON'T HEAR OF THE RIVER. BUT
WHEN WE GOT BORN AGAIN, WE WENT BACK TO
EDEN AND THAT RIVER IS STILL THERE.
LISTEN, THERE IS GRACE. WHEN WE TALK
ABOUT WORKING FROM REST IS NOT WORKING
FROM YOUR BEDROOM. IT MEANS EVERY
CHALLENGE THAT COMES, THERE IS AN
INSPIRATION FOR SOLUTION. IT MEANS EVERY
OPPORTUNITY, EVERY BARRIER CAN NEVER
STOP YOU. THAT IS HOW MEN WORK FROM
REST.
I'm working from rest. No, you can wake
up at 6:00 and by the time you finish a
2 minutes prayer, every roadblock is
lifted. You sit in a meeting, you are
signing deals. You sit in a door, THINGS
ARE COMING. CHALLENGES are brought ON
YOUR TABLE. BY THE TIME IT IS EVENING,
YOU HAVE SOLUTION. THAT'S HOW WE WORK
FROM REST.
ANTI-DEPRESSANT, anti-sleeping drugs.
From today it is error. PUT YOUR HAND ON
YOUR HEAD AND SAY FROM TODAY MY SWEAT
HAS BEEN DELIVERED.
>> I AM NOT A HUSTLER. EVERY SWEAT THERE IS
PRODUCTIVITY ON MY GROUND IN THE MIGHTY
NAME OF JESUS. HALLELUJAH.
>> SO EVERY THAT'S WHY THE BIBLE SAYS HE
BORE OUR INFIRMITIES.
>> THERE WAS NOTHING GOOD TO BEHOLD on the
cross. But that IS HOW THIS IS WHAT
BARNABAS WAS going through. The jail was
the final but he had to work to earn.
Diseases were on him. Then now they come
they come and they put him bring the
cross
and I told you we'll handle this in
Colossians 3.
They now put him on the cross. Guess
what the Bible says in Colossians. Now
Barnabas come back. I show you.
So just go back.
I want to show you something in
Colossians.
The Bible says
we dealt with this and you being dead in
your trespasses and the uncircumcision
of your flesh. He has made alive
together with him, having forgiven you
all trespasses. Look at 14. Having
wiped
>> the handwritings of
>> what was the handwriting
>> sin. The wages of sin is
>> the Bible says he wiped.
>> He didn't cancel.
>> Yes, sir.
>> He wiped.
screen.
It is normal. And when you look at that
screen is as if there was no mark. There
is a difference between covering. There
is a difference between counseling
>> and wiping.
>> Let me surprise you.
>> The day you came to Jesus, a fresh
chapter was opened.
>> Yes, sir. I know men know your history.
That is their problem. They have a
memory of your past, but they do not
have an understanding of your future.
>> So, YOU CAN BE BOUND BY MEN WHO KNOW
WHERE YOU are coming from and refuse to
relate with a man who knows where you
are going. Many have died because of the
opinion of men. There are even people
who never believe you have changed.
Listen, you owe no man an explanation.
You just need to walk with conviction.
My sins are wiped. PASTOR, I KNOW THERE
IS A MAN WHO DIED. THERE IS A MAN CALLED
the late Anthony because it is no longer
I who lives but Christ in me. It is no
LONGER I. THE MAN, THE MAN, THE MAN WHO
DIED COMMITTED AN ABORTION. THE MAN WHO
DIED, THAT MAN WAS ADDICTED TO
PORNOGRAPHY AND ALCOHOL. BUT THERE IS
ANOTHER MAN. THERE IS A NEW MAN THAT
EVEN YOU HAVE NOT KNOWN. LET THE DEVIL
NOT HARASS YOUR MIND.
THE BIBLE says he has cast my sins in
the sea of forgetfulness. In fact, it is
the devil and you that remember anytime
those THINGS COME. REMEMBER MY sins were
wiped.
>> Thank you Jesus.
>> THERE WAS ONLY ONE WAY TO GET OUT OF A
jail in the olden day.
They will put your problem mistake and
put the penalty what you need to pay. So
you are in this jail because of this
mistake. AND AS LONG AS THE PENALTY IS
NOT PAID, NOBODY CAN GET OUT. So if this
man needs a million, that's what we call
bond nowadays. If he needs a million,
have you ever realized when YOU PAY A
BOND, THE PERSON IS released
immediately?
born
before lunch.
That's why it is AN BECAUSE IT ACTUALLY
MEANS WHATEVER you committed has now
been settled by the bond. Yeah. Now you
CAN WALK FREE. HOW MANY PEOPLE have
cases over them but they are free in
this land simply because of what they
call a bond
title and they are walking as if NOTHING
HAS HAPPENED. NOW THE ADVANTAGE OF OUR
GOD HE'S NOT putting a bond he's paying
the full price so that nobody will ever
take you back.
Even if they rule you guilty and they
say you deserve 14 years, HE WILL
ACTUALLY pay for the 14 years. So that
when you are walking, NOBODY CAN TOUCH
YOU.
>> So the Bible says he wiped. But this
wiping happened after something. Look at
that scripture. What does he say?
Having wiped the handwriting of
requirement that was against us which
was contrary to us and he has taken it
out of the way. Having nailed it.
So,
so you are you are you are
anything that was against you has been
wipedus.
HE
RUMORS
WERE WIPED ON THE CROSS.
He cannot be IN JAIL ANYMORE. HE MUST BE
DELIVERED BECAUSE HE WHO THE SON SET
FREE IS FREE.
>> AH, LET THE DEVIL NOT PREACH TO YOU. IS
SOMEONE GETTING ME? I KNOW THERE ARE OLD
FILES,
but everyone HAS A NEW FILE. EVERYONE
HAS A BEGINNING IN JESUS. THE BLOOD
WASHES US AND MAKES US WHOLE. AND
EVERYTHING WRITTEN AGAINST YOUR LIFE.
ANY LEGAL CLAIM THAT THE DEVIL COULD
BRING OVER YOUR LIFE, IT IS NOW NAILED
ON THE CROSS OF CALVARY. THAT'S WHY
THERE IS NO LEGALITY OVER YOUR LIFE. NO
ATTACK CAN COME FROM THE KINGDOM OF
DARKNESS. NOTHING SHOULD EMERGE AND
ARISE BECAUSE ALL WERE WIPED AND NAILED
ON THE CROSS.
>> IF ANANAS AND KYIFAS AND JUDAS KNEW
AND THEIR MASTER THE DEVIL, IF ONLY THEY
KNEW, THEY will not have crucified him.
And now these things is nailed.
And then
they are nails on his feet
to redeem our walk. Blessed are the feet
that carry the good news.
Oh yeah.
The steps of a just man are ordered.
The word is order. The word is order.
You know what order means?
Right. An order HAS COME. WE ARE ALL
TURNING. SO GOD IS THE ONE THAT sir
relationship
MUCH
disciplehip
but IT IS AN ORDER BECAUSE THAT WAS NOT
YOUR WIFE.
TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR THE STEPS OF A JUST
MAN THEY ARE ORDERED OF GOD FROM TODAY
NO MORE AROUND HIM WHENEVER
YOU ENTER that's where the Lord has
ordained FOR YOU THE BIBLE SAYS THAT
YOUR WORD IS THE LAMP TO MY FEET AND THE
LIGHT UNTO MY PATH THE I AM LED OF THE
FATHER THEM THAT ARE LED OF THE SPIRIT
THOSE ARE THE SONS OF GOD WHEREVER I
WALK I AM WALKING INTO WHAT GOD HAS
ORDAINED ME TO ENTER WHEREVER THE SOUL
OF THY FISH SHALL STEP THAT IS THE PLACE
YOU POSSESS YES.
>> WATCH WHERE YOU ENTER BEFORE YOU POSSESS
a club.
>> Our walk is redeemed.
>> I rather stay at home rather than walk.
But the deer will walk. You will know.
>> Because I don't just walk aimlessly. I
walk to my blessings. I walk to my open
doors. I walk to my prophecies. I walk
into my inheritance. My walk is
orchestrated of God. That's why there
must be an instruction. And then now
there is another man.
Women are easy to women after
resurrection.
But in the death there is a thief on
this side.
And the thief looks at Jesus says
there are two of them.
One
is about to die next to the well of
grace. Another one, his ego is broken
and recognizes this is grace. And he
said, "We are here for what we have
done. But as for you, you've done
nothing. Remember me in thy kingdom."
That proximity to Jesus brought a man to
the kingdom. And immediately after that
they had now to confirm whether these
thieves these men are dead because they
didn't want to put them there. The
culture was a man was supposed to die
after 3 days. Naturally crucification
was not an act of of killing people. It
was an act of torture. And the ancient
history OF CRUCIFYING MEN THE FIRST
CROSS DID NOT have this thing. The cross
was like a team. It came from Egypt. It
was adopted by the middleia and then the
the the the the
Romans who are looking for different
ways of punishing men adopted it but
they spliced it up. So what they will do
when a man is crucified
his legs are hanging and he's struggling
to breathe. So you either die because of
lack of breath OR BY THIS REMEMBER THEY
ARE also birds of the desert. Vultures
and eagles they have already seen meat.
But the original REASON WHY MEN WERE
BEING CRUCIFIED in ancient Egypt. They
used to crucify men as offering to a god
called Rah.
So there was a a cross like a letter T
and they will anytime they wanted to
appease the god the god rise the one
that has an eye is a son and all that he
has something like an I and R and an I
many freemasons worship him because of
the powers connected to him. So they
WILL CRUCIFY A MAN AS an offering to
that dity. So the origin of crucifying
man was Egypt in nature. Do you know
they put him on that cross I think from
nine.
>> Yes.
And so the Bible says at 12
when the sun was bright,
the Bible says darkness
entered into
the whole nation
because even the son
could not accept to receive the son that
created the son.
>> Creation bowed.
But there is a deep understanding.
In the time of man, Jesus died 2,000
years ago.
>> Yes.
>> In eternity, the lamb had already been
slain before the foundation of the
world. So what was happening is that the
sun must disappear
so that eternity can step in where time
is not functional.
>> Oh my god.
>> This
was an eternal moment in time
before Adam Jesus had died. Yes,
>> those are lectures that advanced.
SO HE NEVER DIED 2,000 years ago.
He
was dead before he was dead.
>> Yes sir. IS ONLY THAT NOW THE PARAMETERS
OF TIME permitted him to step in time
because man lives in time but the death
is eternal. Yes sir. Yes sir.
>> To deliver man from an eternal death.
>> Yes sir.
>> And so when the sun is rising at around
three
they have to confirm whether they are
dead is a Roman soldier. Another man
very brutal. His career is to crucify
men. That's what he wakes up to do.
And he wakes up and he checks the first
thief. is not dead. Breaks his bones. So
when the bones are broken, you
automatically collapse and so you cannot
breathe and the vitals die. But when he
came to Jesus, because no man could kill
God, he led himself like a lamp unto
slaughter because no man, Rome could not
kill God.
Kyifas could not kill God. Judas could
not kill God. He even looked at Judas
and said, "Do it quickly because I have
just negotiated with my father
concerning his will."
>> THE PRAYER JESUS prayed before betrayal,
it was not my will but I will. So Judas,
deliver me quickly
because I came for this mandate. I am
the Passover lamp. And you don't break
the bones of the Passover lamp. You have
to take it whole. And what you need from
that lamp is the blood. So now blood is
on the head, BLOODED ON THE BACK. BUT
THERE IS NO WAY THAT THERE CAN BE
BATHING if there is no water.
>> Are you still there?
>> Yes, sir.
>> So what do we do?
Not only did I come
IN THE PATTERN OF ADAM,
>> there must be a bride.
>> Thank you, sir.
Thank you, SIR.
>> HOW DID JESUS GET THE BRIDE FOR THE
PATTERN OF ADAM? He went to the ribs.
Took the ribs and formed a woman. There
are elements of Adam that were in Eve.
>> Yes, sir.
>> There was something in Adam that was in
Eve.
>> Yes, sir.
This time something powerful is about to
happen.
There is a Roman soldier with a spear.
He doesn't understand he's about to
perform a major surgery because out of
the ribs a bride must be born.
>> Ah, someone is about TO GET IT.
OUT OF THE RIBS, a bride is supposed to
come out. This time, not to be formed
from the ribs, but this time to be
bathed from the ribs.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And the soldier pierced
and the Bible says water
and blood. Those that work in the
maternity understand when you see water
and blood something is about to be born.
Water and blood came out BECAUSE THE
BRIDE OF CHRIST IS ABOUT TO BE BORN. THE
BRIDE OF CHRIST CAME FROM THE ribs of
Elohim. We came from the RIBS THE WATER
THAT SANCTIFIES US AND THE BLOOD THAT
JUSTIFIES US.
>> Thank you. So water MUST COME OUT TO
WASH ME.
>> But it is amazing. Life is in the blood.
>> SO THE VERY NATURE OF THE FATHER,
>> must be in the SON
>> AND THE VERY NATURE OF THE SON MUST be
in the bride. As he is, so are we.
SO BLOOD MUST COME OUT TO WASH TO BATH.
AND GUESS WHAT? THE FIRST RECEIVER OF
THAT blood never moved. He said SURELY I
DON'T KNOW WHAT LED THE UTTERANCE. BUT
SALVATION IS NOT ABOUT SOMETIMES MANY
THINGS. IT IS BY REVELATION. HOW DOES A
THIEF KNOW THIS IS A SAVIOR AND ANOTHER
ONE IGNORES HIM? HOW DOES A ROMAN
SOLDIER WHO HAS NEVER BEEN TO ANY
SYNAGOGUE, any temple, he's just a
murderer, AN EXECUTOR, WHEN HE
ENCOUNTERS THE BLOOD, HE DECLARES,
"SURELY THIS ONE IS THE SON OF GOD. THIS
ONE IS THE SON OF GOD." THAT WAS THE
FIRST GENTILE CONVERT. I think the
second one after the thief because he
was a ROMAN MAN, A MAN THAT HAD A HARD
HEART. CHURCH, LET ME TELL YOU, THERE IS
NO HEART THAT CANNOT BOW TO THE BLOOD OF
JESUS. THERE IS NO CRIMINAL THAT CANNOT
BOW TO THE BLOOD OF JESUS. IT JUST TAKE
HIM TO BE IN THAT MEETING. THE PROBLEM,
THERE ARE MANY MEETINGS WHERE HE'S NOT
THERE. WHEN THE MAN ENCOUNTERED THE
BLOOD, HE SAID, "SURELY, SURELY, SURELY,
this must be the son of God." Yes.
>> History says that they the Romans
arrested the man. They godged out his
eyes, but the man became an evangelist
in the Roman test territory. You can
take out my eyes, but what I saw, I saw.
It doesn't change what I saw. out of the
ribs, the bride
of Christ, me and you. That's how we
were born. Hallelujah.
And then when he was still there,
operations began to happen.
This was not a very good place.
He
a sentence has to be written.
Pilate does not know what he's doing. He
has looked for some men with graphics
and he tells them, "Write in Greek,
in Jeo,
in the language of the people and Latin,
write that behold the king of the Jews."
I met a document that messed my life
when they wrote it in Hebrew and it was
hanged upon the cross. Do you know what
the people said? He's not our king. And
he said, "Whatever has been written has
been written." In the Hebrew rendering
of that word, because he said, "Behold
the son of God." When you look it at the
Hebrew, every beginning of a sentence
carries a vowel. And the vowel, the
first one is why.
The names that were written, behold the
son of God. In summary of, you know,
names in summaries like you saying, uh,
yeah, behold the son of God. So you look
at B,
H,
T,
S, and then G. Are you getting it?
Behold, B for B, hold for H,
there, T for the, S for the sun, and G
for God. When you take those words in
Hebrew rendering, the word that was in
those word letters was Yahweh.
Oh, thank you Jesus.
>> So it was sure, it was Yahweh who said
to Abraham, I will provide myself
a lamp
because Abraham, you can't provide for
me.
I myself will provide myself.
Yahweh was on the cross
as a sacrifice for his children.
Then
this is where everything shifted
because
Ronnie we have taught Jesus as a victim.
Many of us the image of Christ is this
the suffering
Messiah.
The last words of Jesus on the cross are
very simple.
It is finished.
Tetsty
the price has been fully paid for the
marketplace.
The demand judicially has been fully
taken care of. But the final part is the
battle has been fully
the word fully there is in the three
tallest had three marketplace languages.
It could be used in the market. It could
be used in the courtroom. It could be
used also in in battle. So he said
tetlest I have fully paid the price of
sin. I have fully met the judicial
demand of sin but above all I have fully
defeated the devil. not partially fully.
This was not death. This was what they
were calling the sweet of death.
You know I read the Iran war
and they said
when Ayatollah died he had left a will
and in that wheel he said that wheel was
called the switch of death. He knew he
was going to die. He said when I die
everything in this will has to be
fulfilled.
And he he had said four centers
that were meant to strike. Every center
had a schedule that center A is not
communicating with center B. Center B is
not communicating with center C and
center C is not communicating with
center D. But every center knows what to
do.
They have their instruction. It was
called the switch of death. The war in
Iran began after his death.
There is an ancient switch of death.
Unless a grain goes to the ground,
>> it abides only but nothing. Unless I go
to the ground. Because when you put a
grain of wheat, you don't harvest a
grain of wheat. There is a shoot and
there is wheat.
>> Yes sir. Yes sir.
>> So the devil thought he could deal with
one.
>> But what he did not know in his death he
went as Jesus. In his resurrection,
there were many Jesus.
In my name, you shall cast out devils.
In my name, you shall speak in a new
tongue. Greater things shall ye also do.
Meaning that it is good for me to go
that he may come. He that is the promise
to the church. BECAUSE THE DEVIL CAN
ONLY deal with one at a time. BUT WHAT
ABOUT NOW WHEN YOU HAVE MORE THAN A
THOUSAND? HOW MUCH MORE HAVOC CAN THEY
DO IN THE KINGDOM OF DARKNESS AND THE
BATTLE IS ALREADY WON?
>> YES SIR.
>> Yes sir.
>> That's why they fear terrorist
because you think you have one suicide
bomber when he blows himself they say
they are other 100.
So now you begin to wonder who's their
trainer because we thought we had
finished Jesus.
Now we are hearing there are 120 waiting
for him
and when WE WHEN THE SAME KYAS and
ananas in the book of acts when they
called Peter to threaten him
>> they said this man must have been with
Jesus. Whatever we saw in Jesus, we can
now see in them. Kyifers water loss.
Somebody say
the battle is won.
>> The price is paid.
>> The price is paid
>> and everything is taken care of.
>> Everything is taken care of.
>> And now, are you still there?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Are you still there? Yes sir.
>> And now
because it is illegal for the body,
the spirit has left. Now we are left
with the body.
The body. It is illegal for the body to
be on the cross beyond six.
I'm about to say something that is very
radical. It's illegal for the body to be
on the cross beyond six.
Now the system of heaven is activated.
You thought Jesus had only 12 disciples.
There are others who had government
connections.
Yes sir.
>> So there are men we are raising who have
spiritual authority. But there are men
when we need government intervention we
also have men.
>> Peter has run away.
We don't know where Peter is.
Bartholomeo cannot be seen. That news we
don't even heard about him. They have
all left the WhatsApp group. But what
they don't understand, there was another
backup WhatsApp group. These were not
men of tongues. These men who could
confuse them because they used to hang
out with pilot. They understood the
systems of Rome. They are men that could
call pilot once and pilot will tell them
what you desire do it.
>> Yes sir.
>> Joseph of Ariad.
>> Yes sir. People in the corporate world,
we need you.
>> ALL OF US ARE NOT PASTORS.
There are offices we cannot enter with
the gospel, but you can enter. Yes, sir.
>> There are MEETINGS WE CANNOT ATTEND, but
you can attend. And the man said, "Give
me his body." And because you can't kill
Jesus, he he was laid on arrested tomb.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You can't dig a grave for him. He's not
dying. He must come back. So they come
and they have to take the body. I'm
about to show you something so that now
you understand why some things must
happen, why you must go to China. So it
took
it took a man who is interested in
politics here. Anyone interested in
politics, come come running.
It took a man that is a disciple who has
political connections to come and carry
the body.
Is someone getting me? Is someone
getting me?
In the death
in the death Jesus could not entrust his
disciples with his body.
When I'm talking body here, leave this
body. We are talking about the body of
Christ.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Can we go further?
>> Yes.
>> When Oh, wait.
I hope
Now, so this man
with your wife come this man because
the people who will take care of the
body is not Peter.
Peter is supposed to feed the body.
>> But the people who take care of the body
is marketplace people. And I'll tell you
why I've called them now. The body was
left for the marketplace people.
When when Jesus was in the tomb,
Mary Magdalene,
who was a businesswoman,
>> one of the financiers of Jesus ministry
went to look for the body.
>> Wow.
So business people, God does not bless
you for anything. The matter of the body
was not left for the apostles.
It was left for Mary Magdalene.
She's the one Peter never prepared
anything. She's the one who came with
spices
to give the body a decent send off. I'm
about to say something.
Lord, help me.
You can't tell me you're in the
marketplace
running a multi-billion business and you
are very comfortable
to see the body.
Yet you have a mansion somewhere
and yet you can afford spices
to make the body smell good
>> and give the body. Dead men tell no
tales.
If the church gets this revelation,
there will be balance sharing of roles.
>> The work of the apostles will be to go
and seek for the word, the remma, the
meat, the solutions.
And they camp there in the mountains.
When the church grows, it's not the
apostles who do counseling. They raise
deacons so that they can settle matters.
Those are not. You cannot be called in a
territory to settle gossip issues.
Those are deconic levels.
Now you have you now you have dealt with
men. But now this the reason why we are
not seeing the moves of men is because
the body of Jesus was left with the
apostles.
So they trying to take care of it in all
ways but that is not the pattern.
Can I go further?
>> Jesus bypassed the temple
when he was calling the disciples. He
never went to the temple. He went to
fisherman Peter
called him. All the 12 apostles,
all of them were all in the marketplace.
You know when we talk about ministry,
people think theology.
Jesus never went to the synagogues. He
went to the marketplace to get the men
that were meant to work with him.
Many people in the marketplace, they
come to church as guest preachers.
THEY DON'T KNOW THAT ACTUALLY JESUS
needs them more than he needs a pastor.
And that is why the church is not
growing.
>> One of my mentors told me, "Pastor, you
know, we meet and we brag how we have
CEOs in church, managers, lawyers, and
they have never helped the body."
You hear a man sits in safar. The other
day I saw equity. Equity made 70 billion
profit after tax.
You do you know the first question I
asked myself. Who are the people who
save there? Then I said Kenya is 80%
believers. So no need of asking. Then I
asked WHO ARE THE PEOPLE EMPLOYED THERE?
These are the people who are praying in
tongues for 10 hours
in church. THEY GET A DIVINE IDEA then
they go to a boardroom and they deliver
it.
So we are building Babylon
at the expense of the kingdom.
And the Bible says and Mary Magdalene
came to look for the body. GUESS WHAT
SHE SAID? ONE WOMAN. She went AND ASKED
WHERE HAVE YOU LAID this body? Where
have you laid his body? I have need of
the body. And then she SHE SHE SAID,
"WHERE HAVE YOU LAID HIS BODY? That am I
carried?"
>> MARY MAGDALENE IS WILLING TO carry to
bear the weight of the body of Jesus.
THIS WOMAN HAS A HISTORY OF SPENDING ON
THE BODY. ONE DAY SHE POURED A WHOLE
MAN'S SALARY ON the feet of Jesus and
even Judas got offended.
How can such a woman lack?
She knew what to do with the body after
resurrection.
When Peter ran and discovered the body
is not there, did he did not know what
to do with the body
after resurrection.
Tell your neighbor, "Neighbor,
the reason why Pilate
knew Jesus was innocent
but still crucified him
is because of the people.
The reason why
Ananas and Kyifas
decided to
take him and organize a mass
so that he can die is because of the
money.
They were not willing to lose what they
were making in the temple because of
Jesus.
We might look at these men and think
they are wicked.
But everyone
there are things they are holding and
they are not ready to let go and allow
Jesus to take charge.
Pilate knew he's innocent. Was not ready
to let go his political position.
If they say you are an enemy of Caesar,
you lose your job. Kyifers and Anas,
they were not willing. Business had
taken over. They rather kill a man for
the business to continue. What is
standing on your way between you and
Jesus?
Some things are going to be
uncomfortable if truly truly we must not
take him to the cross again.
You know Paul writes and says that some
of us have crucified him again by our
deeds. He says are you not taking him
back to the cross? Meaning that whatever
he went through, you are already making
him go through the same time. When I
read this scripture, I never saw a
wicked Pilate. I never saw a wicked
Ananas. I began to introspect my life
and ask myself, what is it that is
holding me from giving my all so that he
can have it all?
Because we might see wicked men in the
narrative, but in reality, these men are
like us.
But Jesus looked at them and said,
"Father, forgive them for they know not
what they are doing." Hallelujah. Can we
stand up on our feet and just thank you?
We'll we'll continue from there on
Sunday. The matters of the cross are
heavy.
I want to release a church.
The people that are in the marketplace,
The matter of the body belongs to you.
Praise the Lord. The matter of the body
belongs to you. Let me just have a
worshippers. We just want to sing one
song.
The jail is open. I'm free.
The matter of the body,
we must bear it all.
In your own words, just thank him. I've
shared many things. I don't know what
has landed in your spirit but it is
heavy that that Barnabas was not the
rebellious man. That Barnabas was me.
That Barnabas that looked like a killer.
That was actually me. Did nothing to
deserve what I have. But by the mercies
of God, I am where I am. Forgiven,
redeemed, delivered. I can stand before
God and man. I can stand before the
altars of the Asians AND LIFT MY VOICE
IN WORSHIP and in surrender, not because
of any activity because of what Jesus
has done. Thank you for the revelation,
Lord. Thank you for THE REVELATION,
LORD. THANK YOU FOR THE REVELATION,
LORD. LET THIS BURN IN OUR HEARTS. THAT
WE WILL NOT TAKE OUR FAITH CASUALLY,
THAT WE WILL NOT TAKE OUR WALK CASUALLY,
THAT WE WILL NOT TAKE what you did on
the cross casually, but indeed we shall
be men that are committed to the works
of the cross. In your own words, just
thank him. The Bible says, "If the Lord
could not withhold Jesus, then what else
can he withhold?" If the Lord could not
withhold him, what else can he withhold?
He's not the victim on the cross. He's
risen. He's risen. He's ascended. He's
seated at the right hand of the father.
He's ruling and reigning. He's no longer
on the cross. He's no longer in the
tomb. He is the risen Messiah.
Our handwriting written against us were
nailed on the cross.
At the cross.
At the cross
where I first saw the light
and the bance of my heart roll away.
It was there. By faith I received
my sight
and now I am happy all the day.
>> Thank you Jesus. the cross.
On the cross,
>> thank you, Jesus.
>> If you're there and you're not born
again, as you're singing this song, just
find your way on the altar.
>> If you're there and you're saying,
"Pastor, I want to rededicate my life to
Jesus, find yourself on the altar. FIND
YOUR WAY ON THE ALTAR. You are there.
You are not born again. You are there.
You don't know him.
>> There is nothing you need to do. It's
just to accept that he died for you.
There is nothing you need to do. It's
just to receive faith, eternal life. Run
to the cross. RUN TO THE CROSS. RUN TO
THE place where burdens are lifted. Run
to the place where ys are broken.
Thank you.
YOU ARE THERE. YOU'RE NOT BORN AGAIN.
DON'T BE AFRAID of anyone. Just come to
the altar. Come to the altar.
This is the day of salvation, the day of
restoration,
the day of reconnection.
Yes. Run to Jesus. Run to the
>> I have decided to follow Jesus. I have
decided.
>> It's a decision
>> to follow Jesus.
>> I have decided
to follow Jesus.
I have decided
short time.
I have decided I have
>> to follow Jesus to follow Jesus. I am
>> I am
you
there
>> as you're making this song.
>> It's a decision.
>> It's a decision. It's a decision.
>> No turning back.
>> No turning.
No turning back. I have decided
>> I have decided
to take your follow.
>> I have decided I have decided
to follow to follow Jeside
to follow.
You're turning.
>> Your turn.
>> You're turning.
>> Before we pray for this one,
just lift up your hands. Say, "Lord
Jesus,
thank you for salvation.
Thank you for dying for me on Calvary
Hills.
Thank you for the gift of eternal life.
Thank you for marking me with your
blood.
Thank you for loving me.
Thank you for securing my destiny. Thank
you for delivering me from eternal
damnation.
Today, Lord, I say thank you. Them that
are here, I just want you to pray this
prayer after me. Some of you, as you
understand salvation deeply,
I want to tell you there's no problem
recommitting your life to Jesus.
I rather be sure with heaven than please
men.
There are times I've even walked as a
pastor and I looked at my life and I say
Lord I think we are not okay. I
rededicate my life to you. It is better
to be sure.
It's better to be sure. And I want you
to make this prayer. Say Lord Jesus.
Those that are standing here we can help
them. Say Lord Jesus.
Today I have heard your word.
>> And today by faith I receive the
forgiveness of my sins. And today I
receive eternal life. I confess with my
mouth because I believe in my heart that
Jesus, you died and resurrected for my
sins. And today I submit under your
lordship. Thank you Jesus for saving me.
Father, thank you for everyone that has
stepped here.
Thank you for only you can save. No one
comes unto the father unless called by
the son. Keep them in faith even as we
disciple them. Give them victory in
every area. We give you all the glory
because this can only be you. In Jesus
name we have prayed. Amen. Them that
have made that prayer,
I want you to walk by that door. There
are there are people who are going to
receive you. Amazing people. We want to
tell you you've made the best decision
over your life and God will walk with
you. Hallelujah. I made that decision in
2005. It's been a journey, but he is a
faithful God. Hallelujah. Let's
celebrate them once again. Amen. You can
just ushers help them. Help them through
the door.
Amen.
Father, thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you, Jesus.
There are thrones.
>> They are kings.